<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rickyrombo</title>
    <link>http://rickyrombo.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rickyrombo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:09:22 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://rickyrombo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to House Music - Intro to EDM</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 00:09:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/house/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;House music generally sits at 125-130bpm (usually 128bpm). It&amp;rsquo;s drum pattern is fairly repetitive, with a kick on every quarter note and a snare or clap on every half note (which is optional - not all house music has the snare/clap). The drum pattern is referred to as &amp;ldquo;four on the floor,&amp;rdquo; which I&amp;rsquo;ve assumed is because it&amp;rsquo;s hitting the kick on each of the four beats per measure in the &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; time signature and the kick pedal and drum sit on the floor in a real drum kit, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know the actual reason. In any case, the pattern is a kick every quarter note in a &lt;sup&gt;4&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;4&lt;/sub&gt; time signature, for all the people with music theory backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A large amount of pop songs you hear on the radio or in clubs could be considered house music (generally speaking). Almost everything by Calvin Harris, deadmau5, Zedd, and David Guetta is house music (and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_house_music_artists&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;all these people&lt;/a&gt; are house artists). I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep my examples to some of my favorite fairly popular songs or favorite remixes of popular songs, but the focus is on songs that illustrate some core concepts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within house music, there are more subgenres based on the energy and the bassline. My next few posts will go into each subgenre in detail, starting with &amp;ldquo;progressive house.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re interested, you should read up on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/House_music#Origins_.281980s.29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;origin of house&lt;/a&gt; on Wikipedia. It&amp;rsquo;s pretty interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Electronic Dance Music</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:00:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/main/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;So you&amp;rsquo;ve heard your friends talking about EDM, or electronic dance music. Maybe they were going to a music festival like Coachella or Ultra. Maybe they DJ or produce some music. But your friends have shown you different music, and you&amp;rsquo;re confused. What is EDM? Those songs don&amp;rsquo;t sound the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re on the opposite side of the spectrum. Perhaps everything &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; sound the same. One friend says &amp;ldquo;I like dubstep,&amp;rdquo; and your other friend says &amp;ldquo;I like tropical house.&amp;rdquo; And you&amp;rsquo;re stuck thinking, &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rsquo;s the difference?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re somewhere in the middle, and you know and appreciate the different subgenres of EDM. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re here because you want to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=5l-PjIqPOBw&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;go one deeper&lt;/a&gt; on each subgenre and really understand the what makes them unique. Or maybe you just want to hear what I think are the different genres and criticize my examples. Got a better example? Reach out to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, you&amp;rsquo;re here. Welcome to the series. I&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through an analysis of a few major genres as of 2016, and include some favorite examples of mine throughout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-do-you-tell-what-genre-songs-are&#34;&gt;How do you tell what genre songs are?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Subgenres in EDM are primarily distinguishable from BPM (beats per minute) and drum pattern. Since everything is made electronically (at least mostly electronically) it&amp;rsquo;s easy to establish a rigid BPM. And since it&amp;rsquo;s made for dancing, having most of the dance music at the same speed helps DJs mix from one track to the next. Also, the BPM of a song and the drum pattern are the key factors in determining the energy and the style of dance, which are two of the main factors in what makes a genre in any form of music. Artists and different music providers will generally tell you what genre a song is, but most of the time EDM is listed as &amp;ldquo;Electronic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-a-drop&#34;&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;drop?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo; is the part of the song that follows the end of the main build. The meaning is fairly ambiguous. The best analogy would be an amusement ride such as a drop tower or roller coaster. Just as the cart climbs to the top, the song builds to the climax of suspense. Immediately following is the &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo; - your stomach drops on the roller coaster, your feet leave the floor on the dance floor. The reason it&amp;rsquo;s ambiguous is that some people view the last measure of the build as the drop - think of it as the pause in the roller coaster as you hang over the edge of the first hill. Others view the whole energetic phrase as the drop (like me), which would correspond to the entire ride down the first hill in a roller coaster as opposed to the transition from climbing to falling. All in all, it&amp;rsquo;s around the transition of the song from building to a high energy phrase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;do-all-edm-songs-have-a-drop&#34;&gt;Do all EDM songs have a drop?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not exactly, no. But technically the concept is still there even if a song doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo;-like chorus or even if a song isn&amp;rsquo;t EDM. A song may not have a drop if its build (if any) isn&amp;rsquo;t substantially different from its chorus phrase in terms of energy. For instance, it would be weird to say that tropical house has a &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo; because the change of energy isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as drastic as other genres, although theoretically you could. A &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo; is a moment of hype - if you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t find yourself waiting in anticipation to jump up and down on the dance floor you&amp;rsquo;re pretty safe not calling it a &amp;ldquo;drop.&amp;rdquo; However, if someone else calls it a drop, don&amp;rsquo;t be that guy that tries to correct them. &lt;a href=&#34;http://theoatmeal.com/comics/irony&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s actually a lot like irony&lt;/a&gt;. It&amp;rsquo;s not something worth debating - you will know what part of the song is the &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo; even if it&amp;rsquo;s weird or feels wrong to call it that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;let-s-get-started&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s get started&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll start our exploration with house music. That will cover most everything you&amp;rsquo;ll hear on the radio and in clubs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;row&#34;&gt;
    &lt;section class=&#34;col-md-9&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I&#39;m RickyRombo. I make music sometimes. I write lots of code. I also play some Super Smash Bros. - Project Melee.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I discovered electronic music as a side effect of making computer games. One of the game developers in a chatroom posted a link to deadmau5&#39;s 4x4=12 Continuous Mix on YouTube. I gave it a listen and quickly realized I wanted to make music like that.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;I might have drifted from deadmau5&#39;s style since then, but I still aim to make music for the listener. Not for the festivals, or raves, or dances, but the coders, the writers, and future artists at their computer. I write music for the people who take long walks or car rides, for those taking the bus, and for those who want to escape reality while they work.&lt;/p&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;That said, I&#39;ve had a couple performances as part of &lt;a title=&#34;UNL DJ Club Website&#34; href=&#34;http://unldjclub.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;UNL DJ Club&lt;/a&gt;, and I enjoy a good party.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
    &lt;section class=&#34;col-md-3&#34;&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://rickyrombo.com/img/dj.jpg&#34;/&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/section&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>favorites</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/favorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/favorites/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;loading&#34;&gt;Loading&amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>music</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div id=&#34;soundcloud-music&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Loading...&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Home</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of moving my website from PHP/MySQL with &lt;a href=&#34;http://laravel.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt; to a static site using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Pretty soon, &lt;a href=&#34;http://rickyrombo.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rickyrombo.com&lt;/a&gt; will point to this GitHub page instead of going to some folder on &lt;a href=&#34;http://awestruckdesign.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AwestruckDesign&lt;/a&gt; or website on &lt;a href=&#34;http://heroku.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been thinking of ways to improve the website. Some things on the list:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add play icons on hover&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add SoundCloud authentication&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add page for free downloads (using the authentication)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add ability to like/share sounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start making a music blog/distribution platform for handpicked songs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Infinite scrolling (favorites has it already, now for &amp;ldquo;Followings&amp;rdquo;!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot to do! So far, I&amp;rsquo;m extremely glad I switched to Hugo. I think it will make life much easier, and blogging way better. Bye, CMS systems. Bye, PHP. Hello beautiful Markdown, command line, and Git.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/callback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/callback/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!DOCTYPE html&gt;
&lt;html lang=&#34;en&#34;&gt;
  &lt;head&gt;
    &lt;meta http-equiv=&#34;Content-Type&#34; content=&#34;text/html; charset=utf-8&#34;&gt;
    &lt;title&gt;Connect with SoundCloud&lt;/title&gt;
  &lt;/head&gt;
  &lt;body onload=&#34;window.setTimeout(window.opener.SC.connectCallback, 1)&#34;&gt;
    &lt;b style=&#34;text-align: center;&#34;&gt;This popup should automatically close in a few seconds&lt;/b&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>