<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rickyrombo</title>
    <link>http://rickyrombo.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on rickyrombo</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 01:32:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rickyrombo.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bugfixes!</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/bugfixes-9-11-2017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 01:32:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/bugfixes-9-11-2017/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s been quite a few updates today:
 Added Disqus for commenting (honestly don&amp;rsquo;t expect a whole lot but we&amp;rsquo;ll see!) Added &amp;ldquo;tags&amp;rdquo; taxonomy (look, this post has &amp;ldquo;meta-website&amp;rdquo; as a tag!) Updated &amp;ldquo;series&amp;rdquo; taxonomy to have a description and a page to view all series (don&amp;rsquo;t get too excited, there&amp;rsquo;s only one) Ordered the series taxonomy by date ascending, to get chronological order Added date back to the post listing Added a line between post listings and more clear spacing  As well as some bugs fixed:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Electro House Music - Intro to EDM</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/electro-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2017 22:57:16 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/electro-house/</guid>
      <description>Electro house is similar to progressive house, at least the newer, &amp;ldquo;pop&amp;rdquo; version of progressive house that I call mainroom house. It hits harder, is made more for clubs and DJing, and has a lot more synthetic sounds. There&amp;rsquo;s not as much of a &amp;ldquo;layering&amp;rdquo; that happens. Usually all the sounds jump in very quickly or all at once. In my opinion, the best way to decide if a song is electro house or progressive house is to evaluate how &amp;ldquo;human&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;electronic&amp;rdquo; it sounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Progressive House Music - Intro to EDM</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/progressive-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Jan 2017 01:52:08 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/progressive-house/</guid>
      <description>Progressive house is probably the most popular and most produced form of electronic music outside of the broader genre of dance. Take a look at the massive list of progressive house producers and you&amp;rsquo;ll probably see a lot of names you&amp;rsquo;ll recognize: deadmau5, Zedd, The Chainsmokers, Kaskade, Swedish House Mafia, and many others. It&amp;rsquo;s my personal favorite subgenre of house.
The &amp;ldquo;drop&amp;rdquo; of progressive house tracks (if applicable) generally emphasizes a melody instead of a percussion or kick.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to House Music - Intro to EDM</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/house/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2016 00:09:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/house/</guid>
      <description>House music generally sits at 125-130bpm (usually 128bpm). It&amp;rsquo;s drum pattern is fairly repetitive, with a kick on every quarter note and a snare or clap on every half note (which is optional - not all house music has the snare/clap). The drum pattern is referred to as &amp;ldquo;four on the floor,&amp;rdquo; which I&amp;rsquo;ve assumed is because it&amp;rsquo;s hitting the kick on each of the four beats per measure in the 4&amp;frasl;4 time signature and the kick pedal and drum sit on the floor in a real drum kit, but I don&amp;rsquo;t know the actual reason.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to Electronic Dance Music</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/main/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 15:00:18 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/intro-to-edm/main/</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve heard your friends talking about EDM, or electronic dance music. Maybe they were going to a music festival like Coachella or Ultra. Maybe they DJ or produce some music. But your friends have shown you different music, and you&amp;rsquo;re confused. What is EDM? Those songs don&amp;rsquo;t sound the same.
Or maybe you&amp;rsquo;re on the opposite side of the spectrum. Perhaps everything does sound the same. One friend says &amp;ldquo;I like dubstep,&amp;rdquo; and your other friend says &amp;ldquo;I like tropical house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>site rebuilt from the ground up</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/react-js/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Nov 2016 14:59:29 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/react-js/</guid>
      <description>As I was starting my new series, I noticed a few things on my website weren&amp;rsquo;t working. I also noticed that my SoundCloud API was old which was likely part of the problem. In the process of fixing things, I decided this would be a good opportunity for me to learn ReactJS and just rebuild my website as a React website.
So I did, and it took me a good chunk of a week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about me</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/about/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m RickyRombo. I make music sometimes.
I like music that tells stories. I like music that paints a landscape. I like music that is just music and has no secret meaning, but only if it&#39;s good.
I have a lot of opinions and most of them are wrong. Despite being aware of this, I&#39;ll still fight you. Later I&#39;ll feel stupid, but it takes a while.
Hope you can enjoy some of the stuff I make.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>favorites</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/favorites/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/favorites/</guid>
      <description> Loading&amp;hellip; </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>music</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/music/</guid>
      <description>Loading...  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A New Home</title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/new-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/posts/new-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently in the process of moving my website from PHP/MySQL with &lt;a href=&#34;http://laravel.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt; to a static site using &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Pretty soon, &lt;a href=&#34;http://rickyrombo.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;rickyrombo.com&lt;/a&gt; will point to this GitHub page instead of going to some folder on &lt;a href=&#34;http://awestruckdesign.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;AwestruckDesign&lt;/a&gt; or website on &lt;a href=&#34;http://heroku.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Heroku&lt;/a&gt;.

I&amp;rsquo;ve also been thinking of ways to improve the website. Some things on the list:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://rickyrombo.com/callback/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rickyrombo.com/callback/</guid>
      <description>Connect with SoundCloudThis popup should automatically close in a few seconds</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>